One of my goals for the last 6 months
have been trying to get my agents, my
coding agents to run totally AFK. These
AFK agents have been picking up backlog
tasks, have been implementing features
for me, have been doing QA, and
crucially they have been running in
parallel. So, I've had lots of them
running at the same time. However, in
order to get them to run properly, you
need to handle the permissions requests
that they make. And a question that you
probably have right now is how do I get
my agent to run without it constantly
battering me with requests for
permissions. course you could just go
into Yolo mode and have it totally
bypass any permissions requests. But, if
you do that, Claude will do mad things
on your system like delete your home
directory. Or, if you're in an
enterprise setup, then it might be
concerned about, you know, it
exfiltrating data or sending your code
off to a random third party. So, in
order to get agents to run properly AFK,
you need them to be sandboxed. And there
are a bunch of solutions for this.
However, I was not particularly happy
with any of them. The one I really tried
to use and try to make work was Docker
sandboxes. However, there were just so
many problems with running it AFK that I
won't bore you with now. What I wanted
was a simple TypeScript function that I
could run and just say, "Run this prompt
inside this sandbox using this agent."
And all the tools that I found were
trying to sell me some third party
service. So, I realized I needed to
build something here. And that thing is
Sandcastle, a TypeScript library for
orchestrating AI coding agents in
isolated sandboxes. You can use this to
build TypeScript scripts here where you
simply say run, passing in the agent,
passing in the sandbox, and passing in
the prompt. If you look in any one of my
open source repos, you'll see this
little Sandcastle or dot Sandcastle
directory here, which has a main.ts
file. And this is full of these
Sandcastle.run
little functions here. With this simple
function, you can build really, really
complex systems. You can build systems
that parallelize agents running side by
side. You can have systems that review
their own code and then merge it in.
I've been really, really enjoying using
this and now I think it's time to make a
video on it. Let me show you how to get
this set up inside a repo. We first run
npm install AI hero Sandcastle. Once
that's done, we can run npx Sandcastle
in it and you'll first be asked to
select an agent. Let's select Claude
code, why not? You can then select
between one of the first class sandbox
providers that we provide. My plan in
the future is to add many, many more of
these but and you can also implement
your own if you like. For now, let's
just choose Docker. Sandcastle also uses
a backlog manager because AFK agents
need some way of picking up tickets and
knowing what to do next. My preferred
way of doing this is GitHub issues. We
also ship with five templates here
currently. I mean, there may be many
more by the time you run this. Let's
actually max out here. Let's go for a
parallel planner with a review step. And
since we've chosen GitHub issues, we're
going to create a Sandcastle GitHub
label. The issues will be filtered by
this label and it means that only things
with the Sandcastle label on our GitHub
issue list will be picked up by the
agents. We can see at this stage that a
bunch of stuff has been thrown into a
dot Sandcastle directory just up here.
The thing to know about now is this
Dockerfile here, which is essentially
the Docker container or the instructions
for setting up the Docker container that
we're going to be using. Sandcastle runs
inside this Docker container and it
means that you can just install anything
you like inside here. We're installing
some important system dependencies.
We're installing the GitHub CLI. We're
doing a little bit of setup to rename
the um home directory to agent. We're
installing Claude code and then we're
just ready to go. So, let's go ahead and
build this default Docker image now.
That was really fast and it has now
completed. Our next steps are we need to
set the required environment variables
in dot Sandcastle  dot
env. If we have a look in dot
Sandcastle, where it is dot Sandcastle
dot env dot example, we
can see that we have an Anthropic API
key and a GitHub token required. If you
want to use your Claude subscription
instead of an API key, then you can head
to this issue here that will tell you
more about it. If you don't know,
Anthropic is a little bit funny about
people using their subscription for
these kind of things, and so there's
some up-to-date advice there. For me,
I'm going to copy over some environment
variables that I've had already. Once
that's done, I'm going to go into my
source control, I'm going to commit this
code, and I'm going to push it up
because I'm going to show you how we can
use GitHub issues to schedule some work
for this agent that we've created. So,
let's go to our repo and create a new
issue. Let's say, "Scaffold me a basic
TypeScript template in the repo. Give me
a basic TypeScript application that uses
Vitest, that uses type checking, that
has a very very simple CLI that I can
call. Use Commander for the CLI. Add a
CI script that does type checking and
runs the tests." So, now I'm going to
create that issue, and we can now run
our agent to see what happens. So, after
that, it should be ready to be picked
up. First, I'm going to add this little
piece of code to my package.json here,
which is just going to allow me to run a
script here. So, let's say scripts, and
then add this sandcastle script here.
This is just going to run NPX TSX, and
TSX is just a way that you can run
TypeScript as a script, and it's going
to run this file dot sandcastle
main.mts. So, let's
actually go ahead and run this and see
what happens. We can see immediately
that it's kicked off a planner agent
here, and we can control-click these
logs to see what it's up to. We can see
that it's successfully set up the
sandbox. It's the planner agent running
on Docker, and it's looking at the open
issues here, and it sees that there's
only one open issue. It then spits out
this plan here, which is a set of issues
which are going to be worked on.
Finally, at the bottom here, it shows
the amount of context window that it
used. If we zoom back to our terminal
here, we can see that an implementer
agent was kicked off, too. Let's
control-click these logs and take a look
at them, and we can see that it called
GitHub issue view one. It has a clear
picture and it asked for a basic
TypeScript script out V test for
testing, type checking, simple CLI using
commander. Great. We can see that it's
running bash commands inside here. It's
uh doing Okay, good dependencies
installed. And I've even got it prompted
so it's doing a little bit of red green
refactor here where it's writing the
test first, V test run, etc. We can see
it all happening. It's now moved on a
little bit further and we can sit and
watch this if we want to or, you know,
we can go and have a cup of tea, we can
relax and uh this will just do its work
without us.
So while this is running, why don't we
go and have a look at the main.mts file
here? We can see the planner that we saw
earlier is just down here where we have
a sandcastle.run command that takes in a
name of planner. It takes in an agent
here so we can just change this if we
want to. If we want to do planning with
Codex, let's say, instead of Claude
code, we totally can. And it's also
using this prompt file here. So plan
prompt in here. This is scaffolded by
the template and you can totally edit
this as much as you want to to run
anything inside a sandbox. This one is
taking all of the open issues from the
repo that have the label sandcastle.
It's grabbing all of the labels, all the
comments, grabbing all of the comments
body as well. And then it's working out
which ones can be done right now. So
it's only looking for unblocked issues
here. And finally we tell it to output
its plan in a JSON object wrapped in
plan tags. If we go back to main.mts, we
can see that this then gets picked up
here. We then grab the JSON out of the
plan here and figure out the issues. And
then for each of the issues we run a a
separate sandbox here. We run an
implementer. And this one has an
implement prompt that's just inside
here. So implement prompt. This one
takes in some prompt arguments here. So
it takes in an issue title. It takes in
the task ID, which is the issue ID. Then
it says you're going to be working on a
specific branch. Again, all of this is
just a setup that I cooked up, really.
This is not Sandcastle giving you any
kind of prescription on how you want to
run it. This is just a really cool
workflow that I tend to use in my repos,
so I figured it belonged in a template.
If we zoom back to main.mts, we can see
that the result here is captured in a
variable, and if there are more than one
commits here, we then run a reviewer.
This pattern has been incredibly
powerful because the implementer can
make mistakes, but the reviewer
generally picks it up. And of course, if
you want to do an adversarial review
where you have one agent run another or
review another agent's code, then you
can just do suncastle.codex. If you want
to have multiple different agents spawn
at the same time, come up with an
implementation, and then some other
reviewer takes all of those branches,
chooses the best one, or makes a like a
mix of them, you can. That's the power
of having a totally agnostic setup to
what agent you're running. That's the
power of using your owning your own
process. Anyway, let's take a look at
the review prompt here. It's worth
noting this little syntax here because
this is really nice. This is something I
copied from Claude Skills, where if you
specify an exclamation mark before a
bunch of backticks here, it will run
this when it's resolving the prompt. And
so it will actually execute git diff
source branch branch here. This review
prompt just uses a very basic process,
understands the change, analyze it for
improvements, check correctness,
maintain balance, and crucially it's a
great step for like adding your own
project standards. So for instance, I've
added this coding standards in here that
you can fill in with any project
standards that you want to be added.
Let's look back at main.mts, can see
what happens after all of these branches
get created. We can see that they then
get passed into a merger agent down the
bottom. And this one takes all of the
branches, takes all of the resulting
issues, so it understands the changes
that were made, and then merges them
back to the main branch. The reason we
use an agent for this is that there
might be merge conflicts between them.
And I usually like to have a really
powerful agent handling those merge
conflicts for me because they can
sometimes be pretty gnarly. And so at
the end of this, we have had multiple
agents running at the same time, all
committing to their branches, and then
we get a like a senior merger developer
to pull them back into main. Just this
setup has massively increased my
velocity, and it works super duper well.
And again, Sandcastle is not opinionated
here. If you wanted to make these into
PR branches, you totally could. Okay,
let's go and check in with our running
process, and let's see what happened.
All right, we can see that we had an
implementer kick off here, then a
reviewer. Let's check the logs for the
reviewer. We can see that it found that
the code was already clean and
well-structured. Minimal scaffold naming
is clear. Then, let's see what happened
in the merge. So, we can just pull up
the merger here, and the merger ran the
type checks, it merged in the branch,
and it also closed the issue with a
comment. Beautiful. We can see too that
if we go and have a look at the rest of
our code base here, whoa, we now have a
bit more code going on. We have a
tsconfig.json, we have a
vitest.config.ts,
and we have a few files knocking about
inside the CLI here. So, you can start
to see how Sandcastle is working here.
You can build these relatively
complicated flows using
really nice ergonomic markdown prompts.
You can get it to run on different
branches, and just merge that back into
main, or you can get it to do really
nice PR flows as well. You know, it's
just code. It is a programmatic way to
run Claude code, to run Codex, and to
build these workflows that turn into
these mini software factories. I've been
incredibly happy with it, and I'm really
excited to see what you build with it,
too. If you're thinking about these hard
problems, too, then you should check out
my newsletter for AI skills for real
engineers. These follow the skills repo
that went absolutely viral a few days
ago, and I also post tips and tricks
there for getting the most out of agents
using good old software fundamentals.
So, thanks for watching, folks. I'm
really excited about this tool. I think
it's going to be a really nice
contribution to the ecosystem, and I've
been loving using it. So, nice work, and
I'll see you in the next one.